

Gandhinagar, India 382421

+91-7574944533

imniravhathi@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

I have been working professionally as iOS + iOT Developer for over 7 years. Through those years I have become advanced in developing full feature apps with Objective-C, Swift, SwiftUi languages and IoT technology as well with WIFI, BLE, core Bluetooth, Zigbee, MQTT etc. Although I can easily develop all aspects of an iOS app from the networking layer to the front end.

# Experience

#### **Assistant Consultant**

Tata Consultancy Services | March 2022 - Current

- Contribute to the architecture, design and implementation of consumer-facing features in the UPS App
- Build compelling in-app experiences that will reach users globally
- Collaborate with the product and design team(s) influence the roadmap and product development of
- UPS's App and services
- Create and maintain internal shared frameworks and libraries
- Shape the future of optimised analytics at UPS from the ground up with innovative data tools for analytics
- Evolve UPS's architecture to support multiple authentication flows, account management, and integrations
- Mentor, collaborate, and learn from innovative and passionate team members

# **Module Lead**

Wipro | Pune | September 2020 - March 2022

- Worked as Specialist Consultant for HSBC on MobileX app in Customer Support journey.
- Remained knowledgeable in latest guidelines and best practices to ensure delivery of regulatory compliant service.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

VOLANSYS, ACL Digital | Ahmedabad | April 2019 - September 2020

- Design and build advanced applications for the iOS + IoT platform.
- \* Explored the IoT technology with WI-FI, BLE, core Bluetooth, Zigbee, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, MQTT etc.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

# **Software Developer**

Mobiuso | September 2018 - April 2019

- Design, develop, and maintain native iOS applications using Swift and Objective-C
- Develop user interfaces and create custom views using UIKit, Core Animation, and other frameworks
- Develop custom frameworks and libraries to be used in iOS applications
- Integrate third-party libraries and APIs into existing applications
- Develop automated tests to ensure the quality of the code

### **Senior Software Engineer**

DRC Systems | Gandhinagar | October 2015 - August 2018

- Worked closely with our product and design teams to customize apps for iOS platform
- Implemented custom native user interfaces using the latest iOS programming techniques
- Built reusable iOS software components for interface
- Analyzed and optimized UI and back-end application code for efficiency and performance
- Lead development team in architecture and coding patterns and best practices
- Updated project to latest version of swift/Objective C language
- Key decision maker in application architecture guidance and project planning and execution
- Shared knowledge with mobile development team with regard to the company's vision, opportunities and challenges
- Collaborated with other development leads(Android/ Platform/API) on architectural vision and roadmap
- Agile development methodology based on multiple sprints and continuous delivery

# **Iphone Developer**

Hyperlink Infosystem | December 2014 - September 2015

- Working with iOS SDK and Objective C
- Started working with Swift, the latest apple programming language released last month
- Experience working with remote data via REST and JSON
- Experience with third-party libraries and APIs
- Working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends and emerging technologies
- Solid understanding of the full mobile development cycle

# **Education**

# Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.)

Gujarat Technological University | Ahmedbabd | 2015

# **Bachelor of Computer Application (B.C.A)**

Saurashtra University | 2012

# Additional information

- Birth Date 7th August, 1992.
- · Languages English, Hindi, Gujarati.